bookscouter.com 2016-03-17

# Privacy Policy | BookScouter.com

## BookScouter.com Privacy Policy

This privacy policy has been compiled to better serve those who are concerned with how their 'Personally identifiable information' (PII) is being used online. PII, as used in US privacy law and information security, is information that can be used on its own or with other information to identify, contact, or locate a single person, or to identify an individual in context. Please read our privacy policy carefully to get a clear understanding of how we collect, use, protect or otherwise handle your Personally Identifiable Information in accordance with our website.

**What personal information do we collect from the people that visit our blog, website or app?**

When ordering or registering on our site, as appropriate, you may be asked to enter your name, email address, credit card information or other details to help you with your experience.

**When do we collect information?**

We collect information from you when you register on our site, place an order, subscribe to a newsletter or enter information on our site.

**How do we use your information?**

We may use the information we collect from you when you register, make a purchase, sign up for our newsletter, respond to a survey or marketing communication, surf the website, or use certain other site features in the following ways:

  * To personalize your experience via settings found within "My Profile".
  * To more quickly and efficiently respond to your customer service requests.
  * To quickly process your transactions.
  * To send emails regarding the status of your order.

**How do we protect visitor information?**

  * Our website is scanned on a regular basis for security holes, Malware, and known vulnerabilities in order to make your visit to our site as safe as possible.
  * Your personal information is contained behind secured networks and is only accessible by a limited number of persons who have special access rights to such systems, and are required to keep the information confidential. In addition, all sensitive/credit information you supply is encrypted via Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology.
  * We implement a variety of security measures when a user places an order enters, submits, or accesses their information to maintain the safety of your personal information.
  * All transactions are processed through a gateway provider and are not stored or processed on our servers.

**Do we use 'cookies'?**

Yes. Cookies are small files that a site or its service provider transfers to your computer's hard drive through your Web browser (if you allow) that enables the site's or service provider's systems to recognize your browser and capture and remember certain information. For example, BookScouter.com uses cookies to: 

  * **Save BookScouter.com site preferences** based on previous or current site activity.
  * **Track BookScouter.com affiliate links** to determine if purchases or sales occur as a result of BookScouter.com services. BookScouter may receive compensation from vendors when this occurs.
  * **Measure BookScouter.com traffic and usability data via Google Analytics** so that we can offer better site experiences and services in the future.

If you disable cookies, some site features will be limited or disabled. However, you are still able to use the site in its entirety.

**Third Party Disclosure**

We do not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer to outside parties your personally identifiable information. This does not include website hosting partners, analytics services, and other parties who assist us in operating our website, conducting our business, or servicing you, so long as those parties agree to keep this information confidential. 

Additionally, we may release your information when we believe release is appropriate to comply with the law, enforce our site policies, or protect ours or others' rights, property, or safety.

**Third party links**

Due to the services we offer, we provide links to many third party services. These third party sites have separate and independent privacy policies. We therefore have no responsibility or liability for the content and activities of these linked sites. Nonetheless, we seek to protect the integrity of our site and welcome any feedback about these sites.

**California Online Privacy Protection Act**

CalOPPA is the first state law in the nation to require commercial websites and online services to post a privacy policy. The law's reach stretches well beyond California to require a person or company in the United States (and conceivably the world) that operates websites collecting personally identifiable information from California consumers to post a conspicuous privacy policy on its website stating exactly the information being collected and those individuals with whom it is being shared, and to comply with this policy. [**More about CalOPPA**](http://consumercal.org/california-online-privacy-protection-act-caloppa/#sthash.0FdRbT51.dpuf).

According to CalOPPA we agree to the following:

  * Users can visit our site anonymously
  * Once this privacy policy is created, we will add a link to it on our home page, or as a minimum on the first significant page after entering our website.
  * Our Privacy Policy link includes the word 'Privacy', and can be easily be found on the page specified above.

Users will be notified of any privacy policy changes on our Privacy Policy Page, linked at the bottom of most pages; and users are able to change their personal information by logging in to their account.

We honor do not track signals and do not track, plant cookies, or use advertising when a Do Not Track (DNT) browser mechanism is in place. It's also important to note that we do not allow third party behavioral tracking

**COPPA (Children Online Privacy Protection Act)**

We do not specifically market to children under 13. When it comes to the collection of personal information from children under 13, the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA) puts parents in control. The Federal Trade Commission, the nation's consumer protection agency, enforces the COPPA Rule, which spells out what operators of websites and online services must do to protect children's privacy and safety online.

**Fair Information Practices**

The Fair Information Practices Principles form the backbone of privacy law in the United States and the concepts they include have played a significant role in the development of data protection laws around the globe. Understanding the Fair Information Practice Principles and how they should be implemented is critical to comply with the various privacy laws that protect personal information.

In order to be in line with Fair Information Practices, we will notify users within 7 business days should a data breach occur.

**CAN SPAM Act**

The CAN-SPAM Act is a law that sets the rules for commercial email, establishes requirements for commercial messages, gives recipients the right to have emails stopped from being sent to them, and spells out tough penalties for violations.

We collect your email address in order to:

  * Send information, respond to inquiries, and/or other requests or questions.
  * Process orders and to send information and updates pertaining to orders.

To be accordance with CANSPAM we agree to the following:

  * NOT use false, or misleading subjects or email addresses.
  * Identify the message as an advertisement in some reasonable way.
  * Include the physical address of our business.
  * Monitor third party email marketing services for compliance, if one is used.
  * Honor opt-out/unsubscribe requests quickly.
  * Allow users to unsubscribe by using the link at the bottom of each email.

If at any time you would like to unsubscribe from receiving future emails, you can contact support or follow the instructions at the bottom of each email.

**Contacting Us**

If there are any questions regarding this privacy policy you may contact us using our [**contact form**](http://bookscouter.com/contact).

BookScouter, LLC  
1860 Barnett Shoals Rd  
Ste #103-595  
Athens, GA 30605  
United States

Last Edited on 12/15/2014
